<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gamedev on NODRAGEM GAMES</title>
    <link>https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post_type/gamedev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gamedev on NODRAGEM GAMES</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Geoffrey Mégardon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 21:27:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post_type/gamedev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes: Happy Dogfight 0.2.0</title>
      <link>https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post/gamedev/notes_happy-dogfight_020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 21:27:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post/gamedev/notes_happy-dogfight_020/</guid>
      <description>Major Update!
Finally updating the demo of my next game, just in time for you to enjoy with some friends during the festive season :) Hope you like it! A lot of love and time has gone into it. In summary, it is much more fun and less buggy :) with a new level to unlock. But for those who wants to know more, I prepared a detailed changelog you can read below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Lag and Drop when Debugging Multiplayer Games</title>
      <link>https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post/gamedev/18022018_clumsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 17:14:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post/gamedev/18022018_clumsy/</guid>
      <description>Debugging multiplayer games locally These days, I&amp;rsquo;m playing around with making online multiplayer prototype games.
Most of the time, when we debug our video games for online multiplayer, we run a local server on localhost. This server acts as:
 a file server - sending the game files to the client, a game server - transferring information between clients, authorizing transactions, etc.  You can debug your code logic on server side and client side very easily nowadays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Release: Catch the Crow</title>
      <link>https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post/gamedev/catchthecrown_release/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 12:43:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nodragem.github.io/Blog/post/gamedev/catchthecrown_release/</guid>
      <description>Release and then move on &amp;hellip; Finally! After 3 years of uneven and chaotic development (partly due to a PhD), it feels like that&amp;rsquo;s the right time to finalize and ship my first video game.
   How it feels like to ship a game!   Catch the Crown is the first game I made with libGDX. It is a multiplayer arena platform game. My pride is that it feels like I am shipping an actual game: it can be run, played and it delivers fun (to my friends at least!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>